

#### **SKILLS**

**Spoken Languages:** English,

French (Intermediate)

**Programming Languages:** 

TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Ruby

Frameworks/Libraries and

**Environments:** NodeJS, React, Ajax, Express, EJS, JQuery, SASS, Ruby on Rails, Next.js

Systems, CMS and

Databases: Git, SQL, Github,

MongoDB

Testing: Mocha, Chai, Jest,

Cypress, Storybook

### **EDUCATION**

Lighthouse Labs

Sept. 2020 to Dec. 2020 Diploma Full Stack Web Development

**Brock University** 

Sept. 2015 to Apr. 2019 B.A. Honours Sociology

### **SUMMARY**

My name is Bill Watters, I am a software developer with a deep passion for building innovative products to create positive change in the world. I have experience working as a full stack developer in a fast-paced and agile startup where I have learned how to become a core contributor to a production-level product. Before becoming a software developer I worked in the caretaking of individuals with special needs and the security industry. This has made me excellent at working under immense pressure while showing compassion, communicating, and keeping calm when faced with challenges. Going forward I want to find my next role that will build on my skills and knowledge of software development.

#### **PROJECTS**

Portfolio Website

Mar. 2021 to Apr. 2021

A portfolio website I created to show off my current and future projects.

React.ts

**Community Soccer** 

Nov. 2020 to Dec. 2020

This is a web application where users can create and join soccer matches in their community. Users can also chat with others directly in the app.

Reactjs, PostgreSQL, Nodejs, Express

Scheduler Nov. 2020 to Nov. 2020

This is a scheduling application that was built to add, edit, and remove interviews.

Reactjs, PostgreSQL, Nodejs, Express

Food Ordering App

Nov. 2020 to Nov. 2020

This is a web application is a takeout and delivery app for a single restaurant. Javascript, PostgreSQL, Nodejs, Express

Jungle-Rails

Oct. 2020 to Nov. 2020

This is an online shopping website where users can search and buy items posted by the owner.

HTML, CSS, Ruby on Rails

## **EMPLOYMENT**

# **Full Stack Developer Intern**

Toronto, ON

Jan. 2021 to Current

Responsible for building new web application features in a fully remote, agile environment using a MERN stack.

- Led the front end development for a referral system which generated a 36% increase in active users.
- Developed a new full stack feature to facilitate the transfer of money on the web application between users.
- Redesigned and optimized the login and authorization systems on the front and back end.

# **Group Home Support Worker**

Families 1st

Honeybee

Hamilton, ON Nov. 2019 to Sept. 2020

- Implemented and carried out behavioural support plans for individuals with a variety of challenging needs.
- Fulfilled the daily care and treatment for individuals with a variety of disabilities.
- Responded to the behavioural issues of clients within the home and wrote detailed reports of the incidents.